<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> – Resources</title>
    <link>https://docker-community-leaders.github.io/dockercommunity/docs/communityleaders/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://docker-community-leaders.github.io/dockercommunity/docs/communityleaders/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Community Leaders Guidelines</title>
      <link>https://docker-community-leaders.github.io/dockercommunity/docs/communityleaders/resources/guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docker-community-leaders.github.io/dockercommunity/docs/communityleaders/resources/guidelines/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-docker-community-leader-program&#34;&gt;Welcome to the Docker Community Leader Program!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker meetups bring together people who are interested in, use, develop, and support the Docker ecosystem. Whether you are just starting out, or have been organizing meetups for the past few years, we really appreciate your commitment and are very grateful for your contributions to the Docker Community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By holding the community leadership position, you are participating in this program and shall agree to abide by the following program guidelines. This is to ensure that Docker communtiy leaders who organize chapter events are a respected and professional group demonstrating a positive impact in the Docker ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The document is not a comprehensive list of do’s and don’ts, but rather a living set of guidelines to follow that we will continue to refine as the program matures. Our goal is to raise awareness of the potential for actions that could negatively impact members of the community, not restrict the diversity of ideas and expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are responsible for keeping abreast of changes to this document. If you need further clarification or are unable to fulfill any of the following guidelines, please let us know at your earliest convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;embody-the-docker-community-code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Embody the Docker Community Code of Conduct&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Docker community members should strive to follow our community &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. As a Docker organizer, its especially important to lead by showing model behavior at all times, both in person and online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;understand-docker-beyond-containers&#34;&gt;Understand Docker beyond containers.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a community leader, you understand that Docker is an evolving platform. Ideally, you have a good understanding of all the products including Docker EE. You may feature Docker ecosystem tools at the local meetups you organize, but you are still enthusiastic about Docker as a whole technology and platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-a-force-for-good-in-the-community&#34;&gt;Be a force for good in the community&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promote and support inclusivity, respect, and professionalism in the tech community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strive to keep the group active with frequent meetups and presentations on relevant content (including the latest Docker releases and cool projects using Docker products). If you can no longer commit to being an organizer, struggle to find good speakers or sponsors, please give us a heads up so that we can help out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that all participants can freely and openly share ideas in a safe and welcoming environment that encourages mutual respect and collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep up-to-date on the latest technological advances in Docker and the ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with the Docker Community team to support the organization of Docker-centric meetups and local editions of global meetup campaigns (Docker Birthday, Global Hack Day, etc.) in your local community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;curate-balanced-and-accurate-content&#34;&gt;Curate balanced and accurate content&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When selecting the content of the meetups and/or using program resources to produce content, prioritize featuring Docker-native solutions over others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be respectful when mentioning other vendors, technologies, and communities in the ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select content that is educational, accurate, and free from sales pitches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not accept talks which slander or publish libel against Docker or other people and companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be rigorous in assessing the content submitted by potential speakers. If you need help validating results and analyses, reach out for assistance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When selecting events to promote, be sure the event features Docker-native solutions in a capacity and highlight that information in the body of the message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you experience difficulties with Docker products, give us the opportunity to address your feedback in advance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re subscribed to the Docker Community Leaders mailing list + private slack channel to stay informed about the latest Docker news and community activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;enforcing-these-community-guidelines&#34;&gt;Enforcing these Community Guidelines&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker reserves the right to remove any member from the Community Leader program for violating these guidelines. In the event of a violation, the Docker community team will review the situation and determine the consequences on a case by case basis. When a community leader is removed from the program, we retire the remaining benefits and his or her access to Docker Community Leader resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;additional-resources&#34;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/community/blob/master/Community-Leaders/Resources/Docker-Meetup-Guide.md&#34;&gt;Docker Meetup Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://events.docker.com/get-involved/sponsor-an-event/&#34;&gt;Meetup Sponsorship Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Conduct a Virtual Meetup</title>
      <link>https://docker-community-leaders.github.io/dockercommunity/docs/communityleaders/resources/conduct-a-virtual-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docker-community-leaders.github.io/dockercommunity/docs/communityleaders/resources/conduct-a-virtual-meetup/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-conduct-a-docker-chaptervirtual-meetup-event&#34;&gt;How to conduct a Docker Chapter/Virtual Meetup event&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker Chapter events and meetups are social events organized by community members who are interested in talking and learning about Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is interested in meeting with others to discuss about Docker is welcome to organize virtualchapter events.
The first step is to read and understand our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; and then to &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.docker.com/registrations/groups/1865&#34;&gt;apply to the program here&lt;/a&gt; to be formally onboarded by a member of the Docker Community Team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide helps you to successfully organize Docker Chapter Events. It provides tips, checklists, and concepts to do your planning effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;preparation&#34;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, make sure you answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bootstrap or contribute:&lt;/strong&gt; Anyone can start a Docker Chapter as long as there is not an existing Docker user group in your city. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.docker.com/chapters/&#34;&gt;Docker community page&lt;/a&gt; to make sure a group does not already exist in your city. If one does exist and you would like to help out please click the contact us button on the chapter page to email the local team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team up!&lt;/strong&gt;
Try go get others involved. Spread the tasks across several shoulders, but make sure there is not just a single person responsible who manages all the important information and tasks. Life happens, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to know you have someone who can help out when you&amp;rsquo;re busy from time to time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check: Commitment&lt;/strong&gt;: Ask yourself: Are you willing to make a long term commitment to your community? Starting a chapter is a long term responsibility and goes far beyond your first event. Organizing events is very rewarding in several aspects but building and maintaining a community requires a commitment. We set a goal of 1 event per quarter. Can you commit to that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;structure-your-meetup-project&#34;&gt;Structure Your Meetup Project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decided to start, &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.docker.com/registrations/groups/1865&#34;&gt;apply to the program here&lt;/a&gt; and a member of the Community Team will be in touch. The Community Team can help with things like finding venues, sponsors and speakers and can provide swag for your event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the group is launched, we recommend scheduling the first meetup with enough lead time for successful promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, make yourself familiar with the three most relevant tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://community.docker.com&#34;&gt;The Docker Community Directory&lt;/a&gt;: This is where you applied to the community leaders program, but it also acts as a Docker Community Directory and its built-in messaging system is the main method of communication from the Docker Team. Subscribing to the community leaders mailing list is imperative as all Docker and community information is sent to organizers this way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github.com: Resources, slide decks, sponsorship resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events.docker.com: Publish events and track attendees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community Leader Private Slack Channel: Great place to interact with other community leaders, make sure you have access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you go through the organizing process, you can use the following phases to structure your planning for a successful event:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Images_for_meetup_guide/Project_Phases.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with a scoping phase that shapes the general purpose of your meetup series. In this phase, you answer questions like: Do I want to organize simple, open discussions about Docker or I want to invite speakers? All the remaining phases belong to a single meetup, i.e. for each meetup you start with planning and finish up with the closing phase. Following this guide will make it easy for you to always have an overview what&amp;rsquo;s important now and next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define your scope and goal:&lt;/strong&gt; All subsequent planning steps are aligned to the scope and goal you define. Define, what kind of meetup you want to run:
Usually, Docker Meetup events are 2-3 hours long, start between 4pm and 7pm and feature 1 to 3 main talks lasting 20-30 minutes each. The agenda is up to each meetup Community, so feel free to explore different avenues to share knowledge:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple social gatherings to discuss Docker projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10-minute lightning talks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How-to tutorials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presenting use cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced technical deep dives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target Group&lt;/strong&gt;: Advertising for students is very different than it is for employees. Define your target group to allocate appropriate ad resources later on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequency:&lt;/strong&gt;: Having a regular meetup date is key to an active group. Consistent meetups are essential in building a thriving community. Is there a certain time that works best for everyone? How often will you meet? No matter what your group decides, allowing enough time to travel to the meetup location and holding frequent, regular meetup events are two significant catalysts for a strong and active meetup group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;planning&#34;&gt;Planning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend to create a single planning document, i.e. a Markdown file for each meetup. Using Github for that eases file versioning and eases editing since Github is a familiar platform.
This planning document should gather all relevant information for the particular meetup, divided in categories and tasks. See the following slide as example (it&amp;rsquo;s in German, but you&amp;rsquo;ll get the general idea):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;Images_for_meetup_guide/Planning_Categories_Tasks.png&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each category contains a set of associated tasks. Thereby, each tasks ideally has:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a checkbox to track the progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the name of the one who is responsible for the tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a deadline, if appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the following as example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;Images_for_meetup_guide/Screenshot_Tasks.png&#34; width=&#34;480&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;plan-each-category&#34;&gt;Plan each category&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, see the following tips for each category:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advertisement&lt;/strong&gt;:
General advice: Trial and error. After the third meetup you&amp;rsquo;ll have a good feeling of which ad is useful or not.
Indoor, locations that are often used is highly recommended, such as entrances to cafeterias in your company or at university.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can help with promoting your event across Docker’s social media channels. Once your meetup page is created, we’ll add your group to the global map and include it in our meetup groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker will tweet about your meetup events and include them in the events section on docker.com and in the Docker Weekly newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encourage members to invite friends and colleagues to meetups! Messaging through meetup.com is an effective way to encourage more communication and activity among members. The more the merrier!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join forces! You may consider joining forces with another complementary meetup group with shared interests and goals. For new groups - perhaps in more remote locations - cross-promotion can be a great way to kick start and establish the group’s presence. You can create an event together and then share it with each group’s members to multiply attendance. This encourages and builds the community on both sides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all advertisements, you should reference the meetup.com event page. Changing details on meetup.com is much easier than on physically published ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more advice on how to promote your meetup, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/help/topics/45/article/865489/&#34;&gt;promote my meetup group on Meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsorship&lt;/strong&gt;
The main benefit of sponsoring a Docker Meetup is visibility. As a sponsor, you can gain visibility in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving a regular talk at the meetup or a short introduction talk (2-5 min) at the beginning (as long it is not a sales pitch!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listing as a sponsor on the meetup.com page left column&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listing in the meetup event page event details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks in pre- and/or post-event emails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verbal thank you in opening or closing remarks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognition in the following Docker promotional channels
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker social media networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Weekly newsletter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker Monthly Events blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an effort to keep our meetup events neutral, we mostly welcome ad hoc sponsorships. If you are interested in a recurring sponsorship, please contact Docker at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:community@docker.com&#34;&gt;community@docker.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speakers:&lt;/strong&gt;
In general, good speakers are rare, often busy themselves, but important for a good meetup series.
Even if the speaker&amp;rsquo;s content seems very good, some speakers cannot properly deliver their content. Try to see the speaker once in advance, e.g. on other meetups or do a dry-run with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Message members in the group to see if they would like to present or if they know of any speakers from their network.
Is there anyone from the Docker Team in the local area who could give a talk?
Find local developer conferences, review the speaker list, and identify if anyone could be using Docker. Conferences can be tracked on &lt;a href=&#34;lanyrd.com&#34;&gt;lanyrd.com&lt;/a&gt;.
If members feel that a full presentation with slides is too much of a time commitment, a shorter lightning talk of 5-10 minutes or a quick demo is also great! Everyone can learn something from each other.
Tips for selecting appropriate speakers: talks should not be a sales pitch, but can however showcase a company’s tech and how it uses Docker. We also don’t expect speakers to “oversell” Docker. They should “be themselves” and formulate a talk they feel would be relevant to Docker users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a moderator (can by anyone who feels good in doing this) that leads through the talks. Start with a warm welcome, announce each talk and wish everyone a good safe home. It&amp;rsquo;s that easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ask Docker for an employee to come by. If it&amp;rsquo;s possible to align this to their travels, this is a big plus for the agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t hesitate to ask Docker community managers for advice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timetable:&lt;/strong&gt;
Prefer to run the meetup outside of typical business hours - evenings tend to work best for most groups. Weekdays like Tuesday, Wednesday or Thursday work best: meeting during the workweek gives your group its best chance for a higher turnout (especially in North America and Europe).
Note that in Asia, meetups scheduled during the weekend also tend to be very well attended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When considering the date for your meetup, conduct a thorough search of other meetup groups in your local area that Docker users may already be attending. Consider, for example, when the Go or DevOps user groups meet and try to avoid scheduling your meetup events on coinciding days. You don’t want to force your attendees to choose between events - they (yourself included) may want to attend both!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are holidays coming up or conferences happening close by that your members might attend? Consider scheduling the meetup so that both you and your members can participate in the event, or better yet, create a complementary meetup around the conference dates. Being flexible helps both you and the group maximize the time you have together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsure about dates and times? Poll the group!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event description on Meetup.com:&lt;/strong&gt;
On the event&amp;rsquo;s page, providing enough information about the program is conducive to higher attendance.
Haven’t finalized all of the details? Don’t worry - post the meetup anyway so it is on everyone’s radar. Update your post as details come.
Just note if there are significant changes to the event (like cancelling a speaker); they may be infrequent, but it can affect turnout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post the agenda if you have one. List start and end times, what time the presenter will speak, as well as any other details to let attendees know what to expect. Does the presenter have a biography and photo to share? What’s their Twitter or GitHub account? How about a brief abstract and/or talk title? Let your group get to know both the speaker and topic(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misc:&lt;/strong&gt;
Here, put everything that does not fit into other categories, e.g. brainstorming ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kick-off-preparations&#34;&gt;Kick-Off Preparations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this phase you basically start to do what you planned, e.g. buy equipment, drinks, cups, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit the venue and think about directions you need to provide, get in touch with responsible of the venue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the presentation equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lauch-meet-up&#34;&gt;Lauch: Meet up!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan to be finished 15 minutes before the meetup officially starts. You&amp;rsquo;ll need this buffer anyway :-)
Let the moderator start starting the show, e.g. by asking the audience where they come from etc.
Manage the speakers&amp;rsquo; time by two simple methods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During his talk, sit in the first row. Five minutes before the speaker&amp;rsquo;s time is over, stand up and move to the front in a way that you don&amp;rsquo;t disturb the talk, but the speaker recognizes you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move closer to the speaker the more he is overdue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing&#34;&gt;Closing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phase is all about getting feedback. Really good feedback requires asking for it. Use offline and online channels to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your co-organizers, discuss the event and gather ideas to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Document all your feedback and ideas for next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to distribute the slides for attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If applicable, write a blog post about the meetup with pictures and its highlights. If Docker retweets it or includes this post in the Docker weekly, you meetup receives attention bonus points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;online-resources-available-to-meetup-organizers&#34;&gt;Online Resources available to Meetup organizers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-docker-community-directorytpscommunitydockercom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;tps://community.docker.com&#34;&gt;The Docker Community Directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Docker Community Directory is a simple communication &amp;amp; directory tool for us to share events, activities, and programs with groups of active community members. All our members can easily reach one another. You can open discussions among selected members, send direct messages, share ideas and experiences, get help finding sponsors and speakers and help other members succeed and run great meetup events. When the community supports each other, everyone wins!
The Docker Community page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;docker-bloghttpsblogdockercom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Docker Blog is a great resource to find content! We post the latest Docker news including new releases and events like DockerCon there. For our curated collection of content from the community, check out this page: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scoop.it/t/docker-by-docker&#34;&gt;http://www.scoop.it/t/docker-by-docker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;####&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/newsletter-subscription&#34;&gt;Docker Weekly&lt;/a&gt;
Get the latest Docker news straight to your inbox! This weekly newsletter highlights content from the community along with the latest Docker news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;docker-docshttpsdocsdockercom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get all the info on the different Docker projects with our docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;slidesharehttpwwwslidesharenetdocker&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/docker&#34;&gt;Slideshare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great resource for finding content! Docker’s Slideshare account has slide decks from Docker presentations - you’re welcome to use and/or modify these slides when presenting to your own meetup group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;youtubehttpswwwyoutubecomuserdockerrun&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/dockerrun&#34;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out our YouTube page for videos of recorded talks from DockerCon, webinars and other meetups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;social-media&#34;&gt;Social Media&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/docker&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, join the Docker community on &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/u/0/communities/108146856671494713993&#34;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt;, like Docker on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/docker.run&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and join the Docker Users Group on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/docker&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Quickstart Your Own Meetup Chapter</title>
      <link>https://docker-community-leaders.github.io/dockercommunity/docs/communityleaders/resources/chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docker-community-leaders.github.io/dockercommunity/docs/communityleaders/resources/chapter/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Docker Chapter events are organized by community members who are interested in talking and learning about Docker. Anyone can start a Docker Chapter as long as there isn’t already a Docker Chapter group in your city. We simply ask our organizers to comply with our Code of Conduct and work with them to ensure everyone in the community is feeling welcome!
Interested in launching a Docker Chapter Group?
Fill out &lt;a href=&#34;https://docker.mobilize.io/entities/2371/registrations&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; to get started and have our team reach out and create the user group on events.docker.com! Our community team would be happy to work with you on solving some of the challenges associated with organizing community events in your area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-best-practices-for-launching-a-docker-chapter-group&#34;&gt;What are the best practices for launching a Docker Chapter Group?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attend similar meetups to gain experience and gauge interest in Docker.
Contact people interested in Docker to help organize and promote.
Research companies in your area willing to host an event.
Check out the calendar to find dates that don’t compete with other events.
Understand what topics interest your local audience
Pay attention to the Meetup page aesthetics, add logos and pictures, invite members to leave comments and reply to these comments
Promote the event on social media and invite your peers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-docker-inc-support-docker-chapter-community-leaders&#34;&gt;How does Docker, Inc support Docker Chapter Community Leaders?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We send you some cool SWAG (t-shirts, stickers, etc)
We promote every chapter event through social channels and the Docker Weekly newsletter.
We help schedule speaking engagement from Docker employees and community members when we can.
We Connect you with other community leaders, local users and companies willing to host or sponsor chapter events in your area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-there-any-benefits-associated-with-being-a-docker-community-leader&#34;&gt;Are there any benefits associated with being a Docker Community Leader?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see Docker Community Leaders as members of the Docker family. Although there are no direct compensation associated with being a community leader, we often reward active community leaders with free or discounted tickets to DockerCon, special swags, or treat you to a nice lunch (or a few beers) when you pay us a visit at Docker HQ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-many-attendees-usually-attend-docker-chapter-meetups&#34;&gt;How many attendees usually attend Docker Chapter meetups?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker chapter events range from 30 to 400 attendees depending on the popularity of Docker in your city and the size of the venue we find to accommodate the meetups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-the-standard-format-of-a-docker-chapter-event&#34;&gt;What’s the standard format of a Docker Chapter event?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docker community events are usually two or three hours long and start between 4pm and 7pm. We usually have from 1 to up to 3 main talks of about 30 minutes but sometimes adjust the agenda to accommodate 10 minutes lightning talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-typical-first-steps-after-the-chapter-page-is-live&#34;&gt;What are the typical first steps after the chapter page is live?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post a message on one or all of the following Docker User channels including a link to your new meetup group: #Docker on IRC, Docker on Linkedin, Docker on Google+, Docker on Reddit,
Create a Twitter handle for your group and ping @docker to get retweets
Send an email to the docker-users mailing list including the link to your new Meetup group.
Look for a company willing to provide the venue for the meetup
Find a date for the first meetup that does not compete with other groups
Look for potential speakers living in your city&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;am-i-allowed-to-use-the-docker-logo-&#34;&gt;Am I allowed to use the Docker logo ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are allowed to use the Docker logo on the chapter group page as long as you respect our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;. Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/brand-guidelines&#34;&gt;brand guidlines&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/sites/default/files/legal/docker_logos_2018.zip&#34;&gt;Docker media kit&lt;/a&gt; to choose which versions of the Docker logo you’d like to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happens-if-i-no-longer-have-time-to-run-a-docker-chapter-group&#34;&gt;What happens if I no longer have time to run a Docker chapter group?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We really appreciate all the contributions Docker Community Leaders make to the Docker community. Although we hope to collaborate with you in the long term, we totally understand it if you have to step down as an organizer, just reach out and let us know whether or not you’ve found a substitute. Reach out to the Docker team and we can help find someone who wants to step up and help organize events moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-should-i-contact-if-i-my-company-wants-to-host--sponsor-a-chapter-event&#34;&gt;Who should I contact if I my company wants to host / sponsor a Chapter event?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are always looking for new office space to host Docker community events or new companies to sponsor food, drinks, swag or video recording. If your company is willing to sponsor a local Docker Chapter Group, please fill out &lt;a href=&#34;https://docker.mobilize.io/entities/2371/registrations&#34;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt; or contact the local organizers directly via events.docker.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-should-i-contact-if-i-or-one-my-colleague-wants-to-give-a-talk-at-a-meetup&#34;&gt;Who should I contact if I or one my colleague wants to give a talk at a meetup?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://events.docker.com/get-involved/sponsor-an-event/&#34;&gt;sponsorship page&lt;/a&gt; to get started and have our team reach out or contact the local community leaders directly.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
